Lai Chun Fai, Andy Vice President 9 Bolt Lane, Ketley, Telford

T: 07599242050

E: <u>laihochi@gmail.com</u>

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Hands on project management, business analysis and development experience with different initiatives majoring in Banking and Insurance industry. Before moving to United Kingdom, latest roles in Hong Kong included working on projects related to AML solution and IFRS17 implementation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Manager – LBU delivery, JNL Consulting

2020 May ~ 2021 May

As the delivery manager bridging between group office and different Business Units for the implementation of IFRS17 reporting.

Vice President – Project Management, Cathay United Bank

2016 Dec ~ 2020 May

Manage, analyze and implement Actimize(CDD, WLF and SAM modules) as the anti-money laundering and fraud detection solution with the Vendor, compliance and operation team within the bank.

Managing consultant - IBM

2014 Dec ~ 2016 Nov

Understand business requirements and implement rules in Investment Suitability Engine Client Order systems meeting latest regulatory requirements.

Senior Manager - AIA

2012 May ~ 2014 July

Lead frontend team to manage gaps and new requirements during replacement project in backend legacy core system. Develop a generic tools for regression testing covering different platforms.

Associate Director - HSBC Private bank

2011 May ~ 2012 Apr

Lead the team to build a new data warehouse system sourcing both client static, position and transaction information from a legacy AS400 system into Oracle, which served as the data warehouse for HSBC Group.

Technical Leader - WMIT, UBS

2007 Aug ~ 2011 May

Work out detail business specifications with subject matter experts on products life cycles.

Implement software with developers based on technical specifications.

Senior Information System Analyst - AIA HOMIS

2000 Aug ~ 2007 Aug

Develop and rollout Policy Owner Services system to different regions.

Working with Vendors and local developers.

System Analyst - Aetna Life insurance company

1999 Nov ~ 2000 Aug

Lead in the development of Policy Owner Services system with offshore IT developers.

System Analyst - GlaxoWellcome China Limited

1997 Nov ~ 1999 Oct

Support existing management and reporting systems.

Senior Analyst Programmer - Excel Consultancy

1996 ~ 1997

Work with UBS teams in the development of FX banking product for wealth management customers.

Information System Associate - AIA MIS Dept

1993 ~ 1996

Development and support in Mainframe core system.

Develop and support regional system Policy Owner Services system.

SKILLS

Project Management – Approachable, easy to get along and worked with different sizes businesses Business Analysis – Active listener making sure tasks is accurate and workable Development – Fast learner that evolve with the technology and needs

EDUCATION

Master of Science in IT Hong Kong Polytechnic University 1994 - 1998

(distinction)

Bachelor of Science Chinese University of Hong Kong 1989 - 1993

major Physics, minor Computing

REFERENCES

Available on request